[theme music playing]
[gunshots]
[gun clicks, fires]
[whoosh, slashing sounds]
[machine gun fire]
[machine gun fire continues]
[single gunshot]
[rapid gunfire]
[echoing blast]
[blade whooshing]
[tense music builds]
[Lily] He's gone. Diego's gone.
[Diego] Even though I've left this world,
I'll always be in your heart.
I'll watch over you.
[voice breaking] Diego.
[reporter on TV] The shocking video
of Lily Cruz's public torture
has finally been released.
We will hunt you down!
[Julio] Is this the punishment
you're giving me?!
I am Julio Ardiente!
And whoever you send to punish me,
I'll send them back to you
with a bullet in their head!
Do you hear me?! Punish me if you want!
[Lily] I'm not the only one who loves you.
The people do as well.
And I promise to love this province
the way you loved the people of Ardiente.
Goodbye, Diego. I love you so much.
[Julio] Emilia is nothing
but a stupid weakling.
She takes after her mother.
They're both stupid!
I am the fire that engulfed
your precious Red Dragon.
I killed Red Dragon.
[screaming]
[Camia] Lily, don't be like the people
who killed Diego.
No matter how grave their crime was,
that doesn't give you
the right to take their lives.
[Lily] Not even their deaths
would be punishment enough
for what they did to Diego.
-[gunshots]
-[suspenseful music playing]
You, go there. Follow me. Move.
Go, go, go!
[gunshots]
[water splashing]
-[exclaims]
-[glass shatters]
[whimpering, breathing heavily]
-[grunts]
-[cocks gun]
Papa, you monster. You monster.
You're heartless. I hate you. I hate you!
[suspenseful music playing]
[gunshots]
-[suspenseful music intensifies]
-[gunshots]
[Natalie yelping]
[thuds]
[grunting]
[yelps]
[suspenseful music playing]
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
[grunting]
Men, follow Lily!
Let's go!
You, secure the area! Arrest all of them!
[suspenseful music intensifies]
-[gunshot]
-[bullet ricochets]
[crying]
Papa! Papa!
[suspenseful sting]
[breathing shakily]
I suppose you already know
the truth, Emilia.
You already know that it was
your father who killed Helena.
Your mother.
[breathing heavily]
What are you doing here? Why are you here?
-Here.
-[paper rustles]
-Read that. Everything's there.
-[suspenseful music playing]
That's proof that it was your father
who killed your loved ones.
[suspenseful music playing]
Your Aunt Claire, your mother,
and even your son, Arnaldo.
[crying]
It's all in there. Read it!
That document proves
that I didn't kill Arnaldo!
I didn't have him killed.
Your son committed suicide!
He killed himself because of all the lies
that your father told him!
[suspenseful music playing]
Let me ask you, Emilia.
Would you rather live a lie…
than face the truth?
[sniffles]
-Stop it.
-The truth
is right in front of you, Emilia.
All you need to do is wake up!
[suspenseful music playing]
Your father lied to you.
He blamed all his crimes,
everything he did, on us, to fool you!
You ruined my life
and the lives of so many people.
You did all that just to prove
yourself to him.
[Julio] This is all your fault.
You. You and your weaknesses as a woman!
-You never think, do you?
-Ouch!
A woman like you,
getting herself drunk senseless?!
-Show some dignity!
-[exclaims, sobs]
[Julio] I will treat you the way
you deserve to be treated.
And until now,
I still see you as a weak woman.
[Emilia] All my life,
you've been doing this to me!
Why is it so difficult
for you to save me?!
for you to love me, Papa?!
[Julio] Emilia is nothing
but a stupid weakling!
I killed Red Dragon.
You were just a pawn
in your father's game.
All your life, you loved him,
all your life, he's made you a fool!
All your life, you've been
trying to prove yourself!
But your father will never love you
because the only person
he loves is himself.
[sobbing] That's enough.
-Stop.
-That's the truth, Emilia.
That's the truth, so accept it.
Your father will never love you.
All the wealth you acquire means nothing
because your father loves
no one else but himself!
Enough! Stop it. Just stop!
[whimpering]
Everything you saw,
I planned all that, Emilia!
So you'll know the truth!
The name Stefano dela Torre came up too.
Does it sound familiar?
The legendary Lily Cruz.
What have I done right
to deserve such a visit?
Please, have a seat.
I guess the rumors about you are true.
You are brave, very much so.
[laughs]
What's this?
In your hands is proof that Julio Ardiente
killed Red Dragon.
I only wanted to inform you
that you have a couple
of snakes in your backyard.
I already know
how cunning Julio Ardiente is.
But I never thought he was arrogant enough
to bite the hand of a god.
-[tense music playing]
-[laughing]
Well, Julio Ardiente
doesn't believe in gods.
Don't you think Emilia should find out
what happened to her mother?
Your…
Red Dragon.
And what makes you think…
that we will cooperate with you?
[tense music playing]
What's the plan?
I'll have to take a shower.
I'll be waiting here.
[door closes]
[tense music playing]
Your beloved father, the one
you thought loved you back,
will be the one to drag you to hell!
[whimpering]
Shut up!
Your father is just using you.
He's just using you.
He doesn't love you. No one loves you.
He's just using you!
-He never loved you!
-[shushes]
Open your eyes, and stop being his puppet!
[shushes, sobs]
Shut up!
Wake up, Emilia!
Your father will never love you!
One day, the father you love
so much will kill you
because he never loved you back!
Stop! I'm sick and tired of this!
Whether you're Ivy Aguas or Lily Cruz,
if you want payback, then just do it!
I'm sick and tired of this!
I've had enough!
[gunshots]
Stop it! Shut up!
[groans] Papa!
[suspenseful music playing]
-Papa!
-[gunshots]
[Julio] Kill that woman!
-[gunshot]
-[Emilia grunts]
[rapid gunfire]
[gunshots]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Lily] Where do you think
you're going, Julio Ardiente?!
[Julio] Just as I thought.
I had a nagging feeling
that you were the reason behind this mess.
The immortal Lily Cruz.
I've waited so long for this moment.
To finally come face to face
with my husband's killer.
Diego's life is the last one
you'll ever take.
My life is the last one you'll ever ruin.
I won't let you ruin any more lives!
Go ahead, if you want to be a hero.
It's all yours. But be ready to die.
Because everyone I knew
who played the hero
ended up dead.
When you killed my husband,
you already took my life, Julio.
That's why I'm not afraid to die!
I've always known
that you aren't afraid to die.
But the question is,
are you willing to kill?
[suspenseful music playing]
[Diego] Violence isn't the answer to evil.
We only use guns to protect ourselves.
Wake up! We have to fight back.
-[Diego] Fine, be a killer.
-[Jepoy] Now's the time!
Fine, go ahead and kill. Let's all kill!
How will that make us
any different from them?!
[suspenseful sting]
[emotive female vocal music playing]
[screams]
[breathing heavily]
[Julio] You see?
You see? This is your problem, Lily Cruz,
and everyone else who would like
to be a hero like you.
You want to be a hero.
[chuckles]
I know you've always wanted to kill me
for as far back as I can remember.
But you know what?
You have an immaculate heart.
That's why you can't stain
your hands with blood.
Just like how you don't want
to stain with blood
your husband's memory.
That is why…
Diego is dead, and I am still alive!
Aside from that…
you're a woman.
No matter how intelligent
you are, or how good you are,
you always let your heart get in the way.
And that, my dear,
is your greatest weakness.
You're just a woman.
I always let my heart lead me
because I know that in every battle,
love will always prevail.
I'm surrounded by people
who love me, Julio.
But you? Does anybody love you?
And yes, I am a woman.
But let me ask you, who was it
that brought you down?
Wasn't it a woman?!
And now, she's right in front of you!
I brought you down!
-[chuckles]
-[Lily] A woman
brought old man Julio Ardiente down!
And that's me!
What a woman thing to say!
[laughing]
[gunshot]
Would you call that
a "woman thing" to do, Papa?!
[suspenseful music playing]
[sniffles]
I am no hero, that's why I can kill you!
You idiot! You never can,
and you never will!
[dramatic music playing]
You're just like Lily Cruz.
You're a woman! You are weak! Weak!
You killed my mother.
You ruined my son's life.
I even killed my own husband for you.
You also killed Aunt Claire,
the only person who loved me!
When all I wanted from you
was for you to love
and respect me, at least!
But you never did!
[suspenseful music playing]
What did you say?
I'm weak because I'm just
a woman like Lily Cruz?!
I despise you more than Lily Cruz!
[suspenseful music playing]
If she can't kill you…
then I will!
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[gunshots]
Lily! Lily!
-[gunshot]
-[exclaims]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Julio groans]
[gunshot]
[groans]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[screaming]
[gunshot]
-[screaming]
-[gunshots]
[sobbing]
[emotive vocal choir music playing]
[Lily] I'll take you all down.
-[screams]
-[gunshot]
[dramatic music playing]
[Lily] I'll take you all down one by one
until you beg me
to just end your suffering.
[dramatic music playing]
[Emilia sobbing]
Lily, please. Kill me, please.
I'm begging you.
Kill me now, please. [sniffles]
[suspenseful music playing]
Please.
-No.
-Kill me, I'm begging you.
Lily, please.
Lily.
Lily, I beg you.
I don't have anything left.
Kill me, please.
I beg you. Please kill me.
[sobbing]
[Lily] I shouldn't stain
my hands with blood.
Justice, not revenge.
Just like what Miss Prianka taught me.
[Emilia sobbing]
[straining] Lily…
[echoing] Please…
[dramatic music playing]
[suspenseful sting]
[Natalie] Yay!
[chuckles]
[dramatic tense music playing]
Lily, Emilia was brought to the hospital.
The bullet hit her spine.
She's definitely paralyzed.
Thank you.
[dramatic tense music playing]
[Lily] You'll finally get
what you deserve.
[music stops]
[footsteps approaching]
-Mom.
-[Camia] Lily.
[dramatic triumphant music playing]
Jepoy.
Jepoy, I don't know
what I'd do if I lost you.
I didn't let anything harm me
because of you, Anna.
[dramatic triumphant music playing]
-Natalie…
-[shushes]
It's okay. I get it.
Like, you don't have to say anything.
You know what? You've saved me,
and you've done so much.
And I just want to let you go
wherever you're happy,
and you two look really happy.
You look like you're gonna have
a lot of kids and stuff.
Um, I'll find happiness
someday soon perhaps.
Lily. Are the Ardientes really gone?
It's all over.
The Ardientes are gone.
We can finally live in peace.
And the people of Ardiente can start anew.
[dramatic triumphant music playing]
[lively music playing]
WELCOME TO POBLACION ARDIENTE
[children talking, giggling]
-[feel-good music playing]
-[kids shouting, laughing]
Lily, Ma'am Georgina,
thank you so much
for visiting the orphanage.
Kids, let's say good morning
to Lily Cruz-Torillo.
[kids and Jepoy] Good morning!
Good morning, kids.
Before you continue,
I've brought with me today Atty. Fisher.
Can you say good morning to her too?
[kids and Jepoy] Good morning!
Good morning! [chuckles]
Okay. You can continue playing now.
It's important that I see
for myself how you are doing,
so I can see how the Aguas Foundation
can help even more.
I see you're just like Lily.
You're compassionate too.
-Right, Anna?
-Jepoy.
That's why I had no doubts
about making her the CEO of Aguas Realty.
Not only is she smart,
but she also has a huge heart.
You've put a lot of trust in me, Lily.
I don't want to break it.
Now, I have to leave.
I'm needed in our Manila office.
Thank you, Attorney.
-I'll get going.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, Attorney.
-[Anna] Take care.
[soft piano music playing]
[kids chatting, shouting]
Look.
[soft piano music playing]
[Jepoy] You guys saw that?
I'm sure Nanny Carlotta's
happy for us now.
Same here, Jepoy. Ever since we were kids,
all she ever wanted
was for us to be happy.
That's why, like her,
I'm happy for both of you too.
[chuckles]
[Jepoy and Anna chuckling]
Good morning, Lily Cruz-Torillo.
[smooches]
You are now officially late
for your next appointment
with your BFF. Me. [laughs]
So what now, girl?
Oh, well, I have to go because
my assistant here is in a hurry.
-Assistant? Me?
-Just kidding.
-You're cooking, right?
-Yes.
Lily, Natalie, have dinner with us.
Anna's cooking. She's really good.
By dinner, you mean…
I'm just kidding. I get it, dinner.
You're inviting me for dinner?
-Just say yes.
-Hmm… Okay.
We'll be at the dinner
with old friends. Sure.
But, of course, we have
to go to another event,
where all my constituents
are waiting for me.
-Yours?
-[chuckles] I'm just kidding.
Your constituents are waiting for me.
I'm just kidding. You.
They're waiting for you,
of course. [chuckles]
-Let's go. Hurry up!
-Crazy Natalie.
-I'll text you, okay?
-Sure.
-Bye, Lily.
-Take care.
-Take care. Bye.
-Text me back.
-[Jepoy] All right. Later.
-Goodbye, kids!
-Kids, say goodbye!
-Take care of yourselves. Enjoy!
[kids] Bye!
Jepoy, when we were kids,
I never knew I could be this happy.
But I am now.
You, me, and Lily are happy.
All because of Nanny Carlotta.
You're my life, Anna.
[heartwarming music playing]
[soft sentimental music playing]
"HOPE. CHANGE. LOVE."
-[Carlotta laughing]
-[young Lily] You're it!
Nanny! You're already it!
You're it! Nanny! You're it!
[Carlotta laughing]
[Carlotta] Okay. I'm it!
[grunting playfully, laughing]
[soft sentimental music playing]
[Dante] Come on, Lily! Push! Harder!
A bit more!
[engine starts]
There we go! [shouts with joy]
[birds chirping]
[soft sentimental music playing]
"HOPE. CHANGE. LOVE."
[young Lily] I'm Lily.
Are you Governor Ardiente's grandson?
[sentimental music playing]
[Lily] We will never forget all
the sacrifices you made for us.
We will dedicate every sunrise
here in Bagong (New) Ardiente
to honoring your memory.
[soft piano music playing]
[bag thuds softly]
You waited?
You thought I wouldn't?
I didn't expect to be pardoned.
Damian, yes, you did a lot of bad things.
But that doesn't discount
all the good things you've done.
You've done your time, Damian.
You're free now.
Yes, I'm free.
Free to devote the rest of my days to you,
if you allow me to.
Damian, I didn't wait
just to turn you down.
[romantic music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
-[applause]
-[heartwarming music playing]
[Fernan] You've got a lot, huh?
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
[Fernan] Cheers to the newlyweds!
[guests] Cheers!
[glasses clinking]
-[man] Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
-Kiss!
[Fernan] There it is!
[clears throat, whoops] Yes!
Whoo!
[cheers and applause]
[Fernan] Look, it's the mayor!
The mayor's here!
-[man 1] Mayor!
-[man 2] Mayor!
-Mayor.
-Miss Camia, congrats.
Thank you.
-Congrats.
-Thank you for lending me
-the suit.
-[laughter]
-[Marlon] Lily.
-Mayor, thank you for coming.
Actually, someone's been waiting for you.
Natalie's been waiting.
-BFF, don't do this to me.
-Right?
[giggles]
Oh. [chuckles]
Um… You know what? I'm not gonna fight it.
I think it's really written in my stars
to end up with a mayor.
Would you like to have a dance with me?
-Sure.
-Okay.
[Lily] Cheers to the newlyweds!
-[glasses clinking]
-[guests] Cheers!
[heartwarming music playing]
[clinking continues]
-[guests] Kiss! Kiss!
-[man] Fernan! Arthur!
[guests exclaiming, whooping]
[feel-good music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[Lily] I wish you were here
to see this, Diego.
[whooping]
[Natalie] Thank you!
[cheers and applause]
[Fernan] Mayor!
[Natalie] Mayor!
[glasses clinking]
Oh, Natalie.
[chuckles] She's so cute.
Lily, thank you for everything.
I just want you to be happy, Mom.
[soft guitar music playing]
I'm sure Dad would want the same
for you, and for everyone.
So, I'd do anything to make you happy.
But I hope you can give yourself
another chance at love
if it comes your way.
[inhales deeply]
I'm in no hurry, Mom.
But for now…
I'm happy waking up each morning
feeling my husband's love.
with my love for him.
Bagong Ardiente is really lucky
to have you.
This is my life now, Mom.
Bagong Ardiente is my life.
[birds chirping]
[somber music playing]
Happy birthday, Emilia.
[crying quietly]
[exhales shakily]
Why did you come here?
Just leave me alone.
You aren't alone.
Someone…
could be waiting for you.
It could be me…
or anyone else.
When you're eventually freed…
you'll have a friend.
Why are you doing this?
My family and I made your life
a living hell.
The things we've done--
Why, Lily?
Because I believe deep down,
you're a good person.
That's why people deserve a second chance.
They deserve someone
who won't give up on them.
It's not too late.
You can turn your life around, Emilia.
I'm here for you.
[sobbing]
Happy birthday.
[somber music playing]
[crowd cheering, applauding]
Good morning, Bagong Ardiente.
Thank you for gracing
the opening of our feast.
And now, let's hear it
for our beloved governor,
Governor Lily Cruz-Torillo!
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[crowd chanting] Bagong Ardiente!
Bagong Ardiente!
Bagong Ardiente! Bagong Ardiente!
-Bagong Ardiente!
-Thank you, Bagong Ardiente.
[chanting continues] Bagong Ardiente!
Thank you very much for giving me a home,
and for your unwavering trust
despite everything
that we've been through.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
When I first came here,
together with my parents,
we were so hopeful
that this province would change our lives.
But this province changed my life…
in ways…
that I never desired.
But that's all behind us now.
Our dark days are finally over.
We are all here to strengthen
Bagong Ardiente.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
[crowd cheering, applauding]
Remember this.
No one will ever be above the law.
No one can dictate the course
of our lives except ourselves.
True change is not handed to us
on a silver platter.
Why should we wait for someone
to deliver the change
if we can ignite
that change within ourselves?
We should be the change that we yearn for.
We should embody both order and progress.
We are the future.
So, let's all face our destinies
with courage, passion,
and undying spirit.
Long live Bagong Ardiente!
-[all] Long live!
-Long live Bagong Ardiente!
[all] Long live!
[crowd chanting] Bagong Ardiente!
Bagong Ardiente! Bagong Ardiente!
Bagong Ardiente!
[Lily] I hope you're seeing
all this, Diego.
♪ She's faced the hardest times ♪
♪ You can imagine ♪
♪ And many times her eyes
Fought back the tears ♪
♪ And when her youthful world
Was about to fall in ♪
♪ Each time her slender shoulders ♪
♪ Bore the weight of all her fears ♪
♪ And a sorrow no one hears ♪
♪ Still rings in midnight silence ♪
♪ In her ears ♪
♪ Let her cry for she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream for she's a child ♪
[Lily] I can't say
that I'm a perfect woman.
My desire for revenge drove my spirit
to the darkest pits of despair.
WELCOME TO BAGONG ARDIENTE
However, what guided me back
into the light was the love
I also had inside my heart.
This wasn't just for me.
It was for the whole province.
♪ Let her dream for she's a child ♪
[Lily] In the end,
it was justice that prevailed,
not vengeance.
Not only did forgiveness triumph,
but so did justice.
And above all,
I learned to forgive myself.
Because if we don't learn
to forgive ourselves,
we will never be able
to embrace the bright future
that lies ahead of us.
♪ Let the rain fall down upon her ♪
♪ She's a free and gentle flower ♪
♪ Growing wild ♪
Your indestructible support has
filled our hearts with passion.
Because for a year…
You were with us when we fought…
-When we cried.
-And laughed.
[exaggerated laugh]
-When we went crazy…
-When we got captivated…
-When things got spicy…
-And stressful…
You even made us memes!
It was a golden journey…
That's why we give you…
Our golden thank you.
We are thankful to you, our wildest fans.
-Good job!
-Don't try me!
[voice-over] Long live Wildflower!
[all] Thank you so much, everyone!
[all] Thank you for watching!
[cheering]